intel.co.uk 2003-12-21

# Intel Corporation - Intel Privacy Policy

|  |  |   
  
|   
---  
  
| 

_To read the Intel® Privacy Policy in another language, choose from the options in the menu to the left._

[](https://www.truste.org/validate/2723)Intel is committed to user privacy in our products and services. This policy outlines our personal information handling practices. If you give us personal information, we will treat it according to this policy.

[]()This policy covers Intel's corporate web sites. Some of our subsidiaries or programs have their own, possibly different, policies (see lists at right).

Intel encourages you to read this privacy policy and those of all Web sites you visit.

| 

Your personal information is used in the following ways: 

  * **User IDs and Passwords** —Provide you with access to your profile areas and to protected content.
  * **Account Information** —Tells us more about who you are, how to contact you, and your shipping and billing information. Also contains any preferences you have provided, such as language, e-mail format and interests.
  * **Customer Feedback and Support** —Provides a mechanism for requesting information from Intel. Also used to tell us how we can improve our products, services and site designs.
  * **E-mail Correspondence** —Used to raise and respond to issues and inquiries of all types. Also used to distribute information about Intel, our products, and services.
  * **Transactions** —Show which products and services you have requested.

We will only use your personal information in the ways specified when it was collected. We will not subsequently change the way in which we use your personal information, unless you consent to the new usage.

| Back to top |

| 

We protect the personal information you share with us. For example, if you make an online purchase with us, we encrypt your credit card number. Access to your personal information is limited to people who need it to do their job.

Authorized third-party agents may also need access to some of your personal information. For example, if we need to ship something to you, we must share your name and address with a shipping company. We only provide third-party agents with the minimum amount of information needed to complete the requested service or transaction. We do not otherwise share your personal information with third-parties, unless you have granted us permission to do so.

We may respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process. We also may choose to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims.

We may collect and possibly share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of Intel's terms of use, or as otherwise required by law.

| Back to top |

| 

Intel will not retain your personal information longer than is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected.

| 

We provide links to third-party sites. Since we do not control these Web sites, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted on these (and all) third-party sites.

| 

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information from our systems. Intel encourages parents to go online with their kids. Here are a few tips to help make a child's online experience safer:

  * Teach kids never to give personal information, unless supervised by a parent or responsible adult. Includes name, address, phone, school, etc.
  * Know the sites your kids are visiting and which sites are appropriate.
  * Look for Web site privacy policies. Know how your child's information is treated.

Check out the [FTC's site](http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/edcams/kidzprivacy/index.html)(1) for more tips on protecting children's privacy online. 

| Back to top |

| 

Most Intel Web sites use cookies. Cookies help us provide a better user experience by measuring which Web site areas are of greatest interest. Intel also uses cookies when you register for one of our Web programs. In this situation, a cookie will store useful information that enables our Web site to remember you when you return. Intel can only read cookies from Intel Web sites.

If you choose to disable cookies in your browser, you can still access most of our Web sites. Some Web sites will not allow you to complete certain activities if cookies are disabled. For example, our consumer e-commerce site uses session cookies and persistent cookies to process transactions. If you do not accept cookies, the associated shopping bag will not work and you would not be able to order.

We may display advertisements from third parties. Third-party ad-serving companies control which ads are shown. These ad-serving companies may use their own cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information from you. Advertisers use this information to target the ads and measure their impact.

We use multiple third parties to monitor web traffic, statistics, advertisement 'click-through', and other activities on Intel's sites. Where authorized by Intel, such third parties may use cookies, Intel's Web log files, Web beacons, and other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous aggregate statistics on Intel's Web site visitors.

Current versions of Web browsers offer enhanced user controls regarding the placement and duration of both first and third party cookies. Search for _Cookies_ under your Web browser's _Help_ menu for more information on cookie management features available to you.

| Back to top |

| 

We need your help in making sure your personal information is correct in our systems. Please notify us of changes to your name, address, title, phone number or e-mail address. Most of our sites allow you to make these updates yourself via the program's member profile pages.

| Back to top |

| 

Each e-mail newsletter has instructions on how to unsubscribe.

| 

Intel forums are public. Please consider this before posting.

| 

We may process or store your information in our U.S. databases.

| 

Intel wants to further demonstrate our commitment to your privacy. To do this, we have agreed to have our privacy practices reviewed for compliance by both BBBOnLine® and TRUSTe.

  * Intel is a corporate sponsor of BBBOnLine privacy and is a proud holder of their privacy seal. The BBBOnLine privacy seal applies to our English language Web sites.
  * Intel is a proud holder of the TRUSTe privacy seal. The TRUSTe privacy seal program only applies to the online environment at this time. By participating in the TRUSTe privacy program, Intel agrees in the importance of notifying you of the following:
    1. What information of yours is collected.
    2. How your information is used.
    3. With whom we may share your information.

| Back to top |

| 

All updates to this policy will be posted here. Last update: July 24, 2002

| 

Please contact us by using this form. To aid in processing your request, please include the following details:

  * Contact information (your name, address, e-mail address, etc.)
  * Name of the program where you want the update applied
  * Details of the request (e.g. change of e-mail address, unsubscribe from a newsletter, review of personal information, etc.)

Note: This policy also covers the personal information you provide to Intel Customer Support.

| Back to top |

| 

Check out the privacy policy frequently asked questions (FAQs) listed below. Should you have any additional privacy questions or comments related to this privacy policy, please use [this form](http://www.intel.com/intel/writeusp.htm) to contact us. If you are not satisfied with our response, please contact [BBBOnLine](http://www.bbb.org/)(1) or [TRUSTe](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html)(1).

| 

**Q: The policy was last updated on July 24, 2002. What changed?**  
**A:** No privacy protections were removed.   
As part of our ongoing effort to improve the usability and completeness of this policy, additional details have been added to the _Security_ and _Cookies_ sections. For material changes to this policy, Intel will provide a prominent notice on our Web site prior to implementing the change. Should a change involve a material new use of information, Intel will also provide those affected with a prior and meaningful opportunity to opt-out or otherwise prevent that new use. 

**Q: What should I do if I have a privacy question after reading the policy and FAQs?**  
**A:** Like always, you can send your privacy questions and comments to us by using [this form](http://www.intel.com/intel/writeusp.htm). We will use these items as input to future FAQs. Please do not send technical support questions to the privacy feedback form. Refer to [support.intel.com](http://support.intel.com/) for help with your non-privacy-related questions. 

**Q: Does this policy also cover personal information collected offline?**  
**A:** Yes. We strive to have consistent privacy practices for your personal information, regardless of the medium used to collect the information. 

**Q: What are Web beacons? Does Intel use Web beacons?**  
**A:** A Web beacon is a clear, single-pixel image (GIF) placed on a Web page. Intel places Web beacons on some pages to allow us to compile anonymous, aggregated statistics about Web site usage. We also include Web beacons in HTML-formatted e-mail newsletters in order to count how many newsletters (or particular articles, links, etc.) are being accessed. 

**Q: What is Intel's corporate philosophy on privacy?**  
**A:** Intel is committed to user privacy in our products and services. Read more in our [Privacy Principles](http://www.intel.com/sites/corporate/privacy2.htm). 

**Q: I want to submit my Resume/Curriculum Vitae to Intel. Does this privacy policy cover my personal information I submit to Intel as a prospective employee?**  
**A:** Yes. Intel will use your personal information for recruitment purposes, and if you are offered a job or become employed by Intel, for other employment-related purposes. We have created the [following page](http://www.intel.com/sites/corporate/privacy3.htm) to provide specifics on the Resume/CV data collection and handling process. 

**Q: Does Intel follow the[Safe Harbor principles](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/sh_overview.html)(1), as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce?**  
**A:** Yes, Intel has self-certified for the Safe Harbor principles for off-line, online and manually processed customer personal data. The Safe Harbor agreement governs the data protection requirements for the personal information of European Union citizens, should Intel transfer such information to the United States. More information on Safe Harbor can be found on the [US Department of Commerce Web site](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/sh_overview.html)(1). Intel's Safe Harbor filing may also be found at the [ DOC Web site](http://web.ita.doc.gov/safeharbor/SHList.nsf/2ff3ed061f49424085256967004eddf0/8d5394566934354985256a6c0069a47a!OpenDocument)(1). 

(1) These links take you away from Intel.com. Intel is not responsible for third party content
